Anne Davis

Human Resources Manager

Seagoville, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Anne-Davis/d283181667e19194

A detail oriented professional with over 15 years' business experience in search of Human Resources Manager position. Experience includes employee relations, training, benefits administration, policy management and managing the new hire process. Successful in establishing strong relationships and building trust with employees and employer clients.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Resources Manager

Cinsay - Dallas, TX - April 2013 to January 2015

- Consulted and managed operational aspects of employee relations including conflict resolution, first line coaching and labor practices resulting in reduction of grievances and increased operational performance
- Actively lead and managed HR processes: employee relations; new hire orientation; benefits administration; training; and administering Human Resources policies
- Managed unemployment claims and participated in Texas Workforce Commission hearings; successfully won all appeals saving the company up to \$10,500 in claims
- Set priorities, assigned responsibilities, resolved day-to-day operational issues and managed the performance of a Human Resources assistant and office receptionist
- Negotiated with company broker to receive improved health, dental and vision insurance rates for company and employees, dropping our renewal rate from 30% to 2%
- Developed, designed and deployed office and warehouse safety manuals based on OSHA guidelines

Talent Management Specialist

Artech Information Systems - Dallas, TX - April 2012 to January 2013

- Acted as liaison between Artech and contractor resources resolving payroll, computer, employee and clientrelated issues
- Managed the pre-employment and onboarding processes for our consultants to provide a seamless transition to the client
- Oversaw documentation process on candidate and recruiting activities to ensure company and government compliance
- Trained consultants on company and client guidelines as well as database entry procedures

Recruiting Executive

Sentari Technologies - Addison, TX - August 2011 to January 2012

- Sourced Information Technology candidates utilizing internal candidate database, job boards, cold calling, network referrals, industry networking, direct sourcing and social networks
- Recruited candidates involving a variety of technical skills including but not limited to Business Intelligence, .NET, C#, VB.NET, Java, Oracle, SQL, SharePoint, C++, data warehousing and financial backgrounds.
- Reviewed resumes and evaluated applicants through phone and face-to-face interviews to reveal relevant job skills, work history, education, training and compensation conditions

Human Resources and Store Development

Starbucks Coffee Company - Dallas, TX - December 2001 to January 2011

Senior Construction Representative

- Partnered with real estate and design teams, construction managers, general contractors and vendors to successfully complete new store build-outs; ten-year and five-year existing store renovations; warming and grease trap installations
- Developed project flow chart to accurately track renovation projects from the time plans are received to the time the projects are financially closed, dropping from a six-month project completion timeframe to 90 days
- Created a process to collect \$1.5M in outstanding tenant improvement allowance monies owed to Starbucks in only 6 months

Senior Human Resources Representative

- Provided advanced and confidential support and project coordination for Human Resources Director and team of recruiters, generalists, administrative assistants, managers and field operators producing a more efficient, cohesive team for the South Central region
- Researched employee and customer issues, gathered information to track and manage databases with quantitative information, generated standard reports and identified variances for accurate departmental reporting to senior staff
- Identified and employed processes to improve workflow, organization and communication within and between departments and offices thus increasing productivity by over 25%
- Assisted the staffing organization with the training of district managers and coordinators on departmental tools increasing the effectiveness of system roll-outs by more than 40%

Human Resources

Nortel Networks - Richardson, TX - February 1995 to July 2001

Employee Referral Program Manager

- Created guidelines, provided documentation, trained and supported recruitment staff on referral program systems and requirements which resulted in an 80% increase in referral submissions and tripling the number of successful hires for North America
- Led team of issue resolution, payroll and project specialists, providing problem solving and decision- making expertise to group which eliminated process confusion and more than 90% of program errors
- Designed, marketed and managed the delivery of unique referral projects for specialized technology departments decreasing the hiring timeframe by 50%

Recruiting Coordinator

- Assisted senior recruiters in pre-screening resumes and conducted telephone interviews for information technology, telecom, human resources and administrative candidates
- Designed new recruiting techniques to use in conjunction with event programs which enabled managers to make on-the-spot offers thereby minimizing the loss of qualified candidates to competitors
- Identified, designed, promoted, and managed strategic and innovative recruitment programs to attract the highest quality talent for the most difficult to hire positions

EDUCATION

BA in Anthropology

The University of North Texas - Denton, TX

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

State of Texas Notary Public

January 2014 to January 2018

GROUPS

SHRM - Society for Human Resource Management

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Microsoft Word Microsoft Outlook Project Manager Microsoft Excel Lotus Notes Project View Microsoft Power Point NetSuite Oracle